EMILY-HUONG ERSKINE

UX Designer

+353 (87) 3323600

emilyerskine2002@gmail.com



https://emily-h-erskine.github.io/portfolio/



www.linkedin.com/in/emily-huong-erskine-290280234

Dear Madam/Sir

I am writing to express my interest in any position you have available in your UX/Design team. I have also enclosed a copy of my CV for your consideration.

I am a current 3rd year student studying a B.A. Hons in Application Design and User Experience. My goal is to graduate with a 1st Class Honours in Autumn of 2024. I am confident that my excellent academic achievements and success in my career to date make me a strong candidate for your company.

Though I am only at the beginning of my career, feedback from my lecturers has always been very positive, scoring high marks in my design and UX modules. The approach I take when designing is user based, with research taken from interviews with users having the core influence throughout the design process. I have design skills in Adobe XD, Illustrator, Photoshop, Figma and Marvel. I am confident in coding in HTML, JavaScript, CSS using VSCode and Github, these skills are shown in my portfolio website. For my college assignments and project, I have had to create documentation explaining my design process and reasoning behind my work, sometimes having to present my findings as a presentation to the class.

As well as my work in Design, I have held part-time jobs in both retail and hospitality. In these jobs I have learned skills such as time management, teamwork, customer service and have the ability to work as part of a diverse team. I also displayed these skills while having to train-in new employees. My experience working in a small Letterpress Workshop involved me working with 19th and 20th Century printing presses and I have knowledge of over 100 year old wood type and fonts. I have skills in typesetting and operation of the workshop. I have gained skills in communication in this job as customers would come in to buy the products made in the workshop, sometimes asking for the history of the machinery and the work process.

I look forward to hearing back from you. Yours sincerely,

Emily-Huong Erskine

EMILY-HUONG ERSKINE

UX Designer

I am Emily-Huong Erskine. I am a young UX Designer from County Donegal, currently working towards my undergraduate degree in Application Design and User Experience from ATU (Atlantic Technological University) in Sligo. I am a hard worker and passionate designer. I am creative and love what I do. I have a variety of skills in creative computing and design - from coding to knowledge of design tools. I am positive, energetic, always happy to lend a hand and learn new skills.



EDUCATION

2020-Present Atlantic Technological University (ATU)

 B.A. Hons Application Design and User Experience (Level 8)

2014-2020

Abbey Vocational School

 Second Level Education: Junior Certificate and Leaving Certificate

DESIGN TOOLS







Adobe XD

Photoshop

VS Code









Figma

Marvel

GitHub

Illustrator

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · HTML
- JavaScript
- Css/Bootstrap/Sass
- Python
- C#

WORK EXPERIENCE

September 2020-2024 Student of UX in ATU Sligo

- Working to deadlines
- Submitting assignments
- Building skills in programming, design, presentation, communication and teamwork

May 2022 - December 2022

Banqueting Food and Beverage Assistant, Harvey's Point Hotel, Donegal

- Communicating with customers and other coworkers
- Taking food and drink orders
- Training-in new staff
- Knowledge of cash register
- Working as a team
- Time Management

May 2018 - February 2022

Letterpress Printer/General Help/Cashier, The Pear in Paper, Donegal Craft Village

- Working on a 19th century treadle based letterpress platen built in 1872
- Working on a 20th century proofing press built in 1956
- Typesetting
- Knowledge of 100+ year old wood-type and fonts
- Helping with card designs
- Lino printing
- Responsibility of shop and communicating with customers
- Framing Prints

COLLEGE GPA

Year 1 GPA 79.7% Year 2 GPA 76.7%

PROJECTS

September 2022 - Ongoing

RSA Design Competition (sponsored by SKY), Experiential UX/UI Design (ATU)

 Ongoing project, researching into loneliness and mental health during the pandemic

February 2022 - May 2022

Play25 Card App Game Redesign, UX/UI Development and Analytics (ATU)

- Project for real life client to design an app to teach users to play the card game 25 and for users who already know the game to play seamlessly
- Communicated with the client and users to see their need
- Conducted research about game
- Developed prototyped based on research
- Constantly communicating with users to see if it satisfied their needs and reiterating the prototype
- Reached a conclusion produced a final prototype using Adobe XD and video to the client

September 2021 - December 2021

DeVille's Restaurant, Dalkey Website Redesign, UX/UI Research and Design (ATU)

- Conducted desk research seeing what users liked and disliked about the website and compared the webpage with competitor sites
- Developed prototypes communicating with users and iterating to see what could be done better
- Presented final design in XD to lecturer and class, answering questions about design

September 2021 - December 2021

Hosting a website on AWS, Introduction to Cloud Computing (ATU)

- Group Project on designing a website to store and manipulate data on AWS and host the website on a custom domain
- Teamwork on researching and gathering data
- Exploring AWS features and what we could use to inhance
- Website coded using HTML, CSS and Javascript
- Group project video presentation and Q&A submitted

COLLEGE MODULES

UX/UI Development and Analytics

93%

UX/UI Research and Design

83%

Server-side Web Development

68%

Web Design and Development

53%

Design Thinking

91%

Web Design Fundamentals

71%

Internet of Things

94%

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Student Representative for the Faculty of Engineering and Design at ATU 2022-Present
- Student Ambassador for University 2021-Present
- Founder/Chairperson/Couch of ATU Karate Club 2021-Present
- University Class Rep 2020-2022

CONTACT

+353 (87) 3323600

emilyerskine2002@gmail.com

https://emily-h-erskine.github.io/portfolio/

www.linkedin.com/in/emily-huong-erskine-290280234